Guide to the John E. Fleming Papers, 1962-2013 RL.11014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Organizational Files, 1963-2013
  - Consulting, Early Professional Work, Professional Affiliations, and Community Service, 1960s-2010s; 3
    - American Anthropological Association, 2005 (Box 5)
      "Understanding Race and Human Variation" advisors meetings, etc.
    - American Association for State and Local History, 2008 Sept (Box 5)
      Annual meeting and Award for Distinction.
    - American Association of Museums, 1998-2000; 2 folders (Box 5)
      Accreditation Commission materials, including accreditation of the NC Museum of History.
    - Anacostia Southeast Federal Credit Union, 1975 (Box 5)
      Credit Committee.
    - Artsmart Consulting, Inc., 1999 (Box 5)
    - Birmingham Civil Rights Institute, 2011 (Box 5)
      Consulting re: strategic planning.
    - Brown vs. Board National Historic Site, 2001 (Box 5)
    - Charles H. Wright Museum of African American History, Detroit, 2001 (Box 5)
      Consulting re: grant proposals, etc.
    - Dayton Peace Museum, 2008 (Box 5)
    - Friends of Malawi, 2000-2004 (Box 5)
      Directory and newsletter.
    - Getty Leadership Institute, 2001; 2 folders (Box 6)
      Advisory Committee and materials relating to Fleming's attendance of the Museum Management Institute.
    - History Museum of Burke County, 2005-2006 (Box 6)
    - International Civil Rights Center and Museum, 2002 (Box 6)
      Academic Advisory Panel.
    - John P. Parker Historical Society, 1997-1999 (Box 6)
    - Leadership Cincinnatti XXV, 2001-2002; 7 folders (Box 6)
      Materials from Fleming's participation in a year-long curriculum for Cincinnatti civic leaders, including sessions on justice, health, diversity, arts, education, government, housing, etc.
    - The Links, Inc., 1992-1996 (Box 6)
      Cookin' Men fundraiser.
    - Living and Working in Miami Valley, 2002-2005; 2 folders (Box 6)
      Wright State University and NEH grant proposals.
    - MacArthur Foundation, 1992-1998 (Box 6)
    - Men's Group of Yellow Springs, 1995-1998 (Box 6)
    - Mother Bethel Foundation, 2004-2005 (Box 6)
      Consulting re: the Richard and Sarah Allen Center.
    - Muhammed Ali Center, 1999-2000 (Box 6)
      Consulting project.
    - National Association of Black Storytellers, 2008 (Box 6)
      Zora Neale Hurston award.
    - National Constitution Center, 1998-2003 (Box 7)
      Distinguished Scholars Panel.
    - National Museum of African American History, 1991, 2006-2008 (Box 7)
      Presidential Commission and other materials.
    - National Park Service, 2001 (Box 7)
      Participation in Forum to Develop a Model Undergraduate Course in Historic Preservation
    - Ohio Historic Site Preservation Advisory Board, 2007-2010 (Box 7)
    - Ohio Historical Records Advisory Board, 2004 (Box 7)
      Includes oath.
    - Ohio Historical Society, 2010 (Box 7)
    - Peace Corps, 1967-1970 (Box 7)
      Miscellaneous correspondence, etc. Includes Fleming's Malawi driver's license.
    - Peace Corps alumni activities, 2001; 2 folders (Box 7)
      Ohio State University conference participation; Franklin William Award materials.
    - Roots Project, NAACP, 1979 (Box 7)
    - Sapelo Island Cultural and Revitalization Society, 2009 (Box 7)
    - Santa Fe History Museum, 1999 (Box 7)
      Micro-conference.
    - Sigma Pi Phi, 1989-2005; 6 folders (Box 7)
      Includes membership materials, meeting minutes and agendas, publications, and work from the Long Range Planning Committee and the Education Committee.
    - Soloman Northup project, undated (Box 7)
    - Southwest Ohio Returned Peace Corps Volunteer Organization, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Symposium on the Future of African American Men: Mind, Body, and Soul in the 21st Century, 2006 July (Box 7)
    - Tender Mercies, 2004-2008 (Box 7)
      Board materials and Speaker Manual.
    - Tinner Hill Advisory Group, 2008-2009 (Box 7)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1971 (Box 7)
      Correspondence and other materials from Fleming's work as a program analyst.
    - U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum, 2005; 2 folders (Box 7)
      Consulting work, including an evaluation of the permanent exhibition.
    - Yellow Springs Arts Council/Yellow Springs Center for the Arts, 2007-2008 (Box 7)
    - Youth Pride, Inc., 1970; 2 folders (Box 7)
      Correspondence, time sheets, and manuals from Fleming's work in the Skills Dept. with Youth Pride, Inc. Includes correspondence to Marion Barry.
  - Institute for the Study of Educational Policy, Howard University, 1970s; 17
    Fleming was a Senior Fellow at the Institute for the Study of Educational Policy from 1974 to 1980. This subseries is divided into two parts: Fleming's subject files, collected during his time at ISEP, and then general files from his work at ISEP. Many of the materials focus on the impact and viability of affirmative action in higher education. Another notable project Fleming worked on during this period was the E Pluribus Unum project with Miami Dade Communite College, which sought to develop a new curriculum or textbook for the teaching of American history. Additional materials from Fleming's work at ISEP can be found in the Writings Series.
    - Subject Files, 5
      - Affirmative Action articles (Box 28)
      - Affirmative Action in Education, 1977-1978; 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Affirmative Action and Equal Opportunity (Box 28)
      - Affirmative Action, Testing Merit (Box 28)
      - Affirmative Action, Weber, and related information (Box 28)
      - The Bakke Case (Box 29)
      - The Bakke Case articles (Box 29)
      - BEOG (Box 29)
      - Blacks in Higher Education (Box 29)
      - Children Television International (Box 29)
      - Economics and Race (Box 29)
      - Economics, State of Black America, 2 folders (Box 29)
      - EEOC (Box 29)
      - Title III Program (Box 29)
      - Weber Case (Box 29)
    - General Files, 6
      - A Survey of Minority Professionals in Higher Education (Box 29)
      - American Association for Affirmative Action, 1980 Apr. 30 - May 2 (Box 29)
      - The Case for Affirmative Action for Blacks in Higher Education Documents (Box 29)
      - Affirmative Action for Blacks in Higher Education: A Report, 1978 (Box 29)
      - Civil Rights Reorganization Task Force (Box 29)
      - College Profiles: Mays, Wright (Box 29)
      - Daedalus Essay on Blacks (Box 29)
      - Events (Box 29)
      - Gerald Gill (Box 29)
      - IAOHRA Conference, 1979 July (Box 29)
      - Institute for Economic Development (Box 29)
      - Institute Policy Statement Concerning the Bakke Decision, 1978 Sept (Box 29)
      - Journal of Negro History (Box 29)
      - Letter to Editor: Reaction to Affirmative Action, 1975 (Box 29)
      - Lilly Endowment Conference, 1979 June 3-6 (Box 29)
      - Miami-Dade Community College, 2 folders (Box 29)
      - E Pluribus Unum Project, 1977-1979; 3 folders (Box 30)
        NEH grant proposal, Board of Scholars meetings, and other materials related to the American history curriculum project.
      - National Urban League, 2 folders (Box 30)
      - NCCU Trip, 1980 Mar 19-21 (Box 30)
      - Resumes and Biographical Statements (Box 30)
      - Summary of Equal Opportunity for Blacks in Higher Education, 1975 (Box 30)
      - University of Wisconsin Materials (Box 30)
      - Correspondence, 1978-1979; 2 folders (Box 30)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 30)
      - Miscellaneous Research (Box 30)
      - Miscellaneous Research and Notes (Box 30)
  - Association for the Study of African American Life and History, 1975-2011; 10
    Fleming was president of ASALH from 2007 to 2009. This subseries includes materials from his membership and leadership, including annual meeting materials; executive council and board materials; Black History Month promotions, fundraising, and programming; and other files relating to his ASALH service.
    - Executive committee minutes and council members, 2004 (Box 16)
    - Pittsburgh, 2004 Sept. 28-Oct. 3 (Box 16)
    - Executive council meetings, 2005-2006; 4 folders (Box 17)
    - Board reports, 2007 Oct. (Box 17)
    - Board meeting documents and notes, 2007 May 23 (Box 17)
    - Executive council meetings, 2008-2009; 7 folders (Box 17)
    - Annual meeting report, 2009 (Box 17)
    - Follow-up/administration, 2009 (Box 17)
    - Conference calls, follow-up, 2009 (Box 17)
    - Executive council information packet, undated (Box 17)
    - Financial statements and independent auditor's report, 2002-2003 (Box 17)
    - Budget, 2007 (Box 17)
    - Budget mid-year, 2007 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous financial documents, 2008 (Box 17)
    - Executive director search, 2004 (Box 17)
    - Cincinnati convention planning, 2009 (Box 17)
    - General membership business meeting, 2004 Sept. 30 (Box 17)
    - Brown and the Ordeal of Integrationism in Black Identity, 2004 Sept. 30 (Box 17)
    - Retreat, 2005 June (Box 17)
    - DC meeting and fundraising consultant, 2007 (Box 18)
    - Washington DC itinerary, 2007 Feb. 12-13 (Box 18)
    - Meeting report, 2007 June 28-30 (Box 18)
    - ASALH meetings with Macy's, 2007 Aug. 28 (Box 18)
    - Freedom's Sisters, Washington DC, 2007 Sept. (Box 18)
    - Campaign and strategic planning meeting, 2007 Dec. 3 (Box 18)
    - Transitions meeting, Washington DC, 2007 Dec. 14-17 (Box 18)
    - Development committee meeting, 2008 Nov. 11-12 (Box 18)
    - Barbara's notes: local arrangements committee, 2009 Jun. 25 (Box 18)
    - Teleconference calls, 2009, 2012 (Box 18)
    - General membership meeting, 2009 Oct. 1 (Box 18)
    - Nominations, 2005-2006 (Box 18)
    - Nominating Committee, 2007 (Box 18)
    - Class of 2008 nominations (Box 18)
    - Election, 2009 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, 2006-2008 (Box 18)
    - Annual meetings, 1975-2009; 16 folders (Box 18)
      Programs, notes, and other materials from Fleming's attendance at ASALH's annual meetings, sometimes called conventions. Years included are 1975-1977, 1980, 1982, 1983, 1989, 1991, 1996, 2004, 2005, 2007-2012. The file for the 1983 annual meeting includes a program with Rosa Parks' autograph.
    - Annual meetings, 2010-2012; 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Black History luncheons, 2007-2011; 4 folders (Box 19)
    - President's reports, 2004, 2006, 2009; 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Draft: Special Resource Study for Carter G. Woodson home, Jan-01 (Box 19)
    - Speech re: Carter G. Woodson, undated (Box 19)
    - ASALH-NPS planning meeting, 2007 Dec. 3 (Box 19)
    - CG Woodson birthday, Washington DC, 2007 Dec. 19 (Box 19)
    - ASALH/NPS meeting: Carter G. Woodson home site, 2008 June 26-27 (Box 19)
    - Woodson House report, undated (Box 19)
    - 50 Percent Draft of the Carter G. Woodson Home Historic Resource study, 2009 Jun. (Box 19)
    - Planning workshop, Woodson Home, 2009 Nov. 4 (Box 19)
    - Planning conference report, 1980 Jan. (Box 19)
    - Tips for celebrating "Black History Month", undated (Box 19)
    - Memo and documentation re: term "Black History Month", 2007 Oct. 3 (Box 19)
    - Black history theme poster, 2003 (Box 19)
    - ASALH headquarters at 636 Q St NW, 2007 and undated (Box 19)
    - American Advertising Association, undated (Box 19)
    - Archives package, 2009 (Box 19)
    - ASALH documents, undated (Box 19)
    - ASALH store promotional materials, 2007 (Box 19)
    - Barbara Glass, undated (Box 19)
    - Branding case statement, undated (Box 19)
    - Calendar, 2008 (Box 19)
    - Capital campaign, 2007 (Box 19)
    - Clippings, 2006 (Box 19)
    - Coca-Cola, 2008 (Box 19)
    - Constitution and by-laws, 2006 Sept. 28 (Box 19)
    - Corporate fundraising, 2007 (Box 19)
    - Dave Hobson, federal funding, 2007 (Box 19)
    - The Desegregation of Public Accomodations (Robert M. Preston), 1979 Oct. 26 (Box 19)
    - Development ideas, 2007 (Box 19)
    - Dreck Wilson, 2009 (Box 19)
    - Duke Energy proposal, 2007 (Box 19)
    - Fact sheet, undated (Box 19)
    - Federal Dept Stores proposal, 2007 (Box 19)
    - Fundraising, 2006 (Box 19)
    - Fudraising agreement between the NPS and ASALH, 2007 (Box 19)
    - Fundraising project, 2008 (Box 19)
    - Hemmer construction, 2007 (Box 19)
    - Historical background, 2006 (Box 19)
    - IMLS grant ideas, 2006 (Box 19)
    - IMLS grant information, 2007 (Box 20)
    - Investment policy manual, undated (Box 20)
    - Investment strategy, 2007 (Box 20)
    - Letterhead, undated (Box 20)
    - Membership cards, 2008 (Box 20)
    - Morehouse, 2006 (Box 20)
    - Oral History Project, 1978 (Box 20)
    - PR and marketing, undated (Box 20)
    - Small Business Administration, undated (Box 20)
    - Summary of ASALH Housing Crisis, 2008 (Box 20)
    - To do lists, status reports, 2007-2008 (Box 20)
    - Toyota proposal, 2007 (Box 20)
    - White House photos, undated (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous, 2004-2009 (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous documents and notes, 2006 (Box 20)
  - African American Museums Association/Association for African American Museums, 1986-2011; 11
    - Accounting funds, 1998 (Box 20)
    - Blacks in Museums, 1986-1987 (Box 20)
    - Blacks in Museums: A Directory of African American Museums and Museum Professionals, 1993 (Box 20)
    - Board meeting, 1998 March 13-14 (Box 20)
    - Financial documents, 1997-1998 (Box 20)
    - NPS workshop, 1998 Oct. 13-15 (Box 20)
    - Profile of Black Museums, 1988 (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1992-1998 (Box 20)
    - AAAM Board, 2001-2005 (Box 20)
    - AAAM and National Conference of Artists Conference, 1998 Aug. 27-28 (Box 20)
    - Annual conferences, 2007-2011; 5 folders (Box 20)
    - Assessment of the Field: African American Cultural Organizations, 2008 Sept. (Box 20)
    - Contact lists, 2003 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 20)
    - Directors' roundtable, 2007 Aug. 31 (Box 20)
    - Directory, 1998-1999 (Box 20)
    - Membership documents, 1998-2000 (Box 20)
    - Membership list, 2005 (Box 20)
    - Policy and Procedures Manual (draft), 1998 (Box 20)
    - The Scrip newsletter, 2006-2009 (Box 20)
  - Berea College Board of Trustees, 1994-2013; 13
    This subseries contains materials from Fleming's service and support of the Berea College (Kentucky) Board of Trustees, including board meetings, Berea publications, trustee administrative files, and committee work. Also includes a file on Fleming's establishment of the Ward/Ivory endowment at Berea.
    - Board of Trustees meetings, 2007 Oct.-2011 May; 12 folders (Box 22)
      The BOT met three times per year, in February, May, and October. These files include meeting packets prepared for each BOT member as well as Fleming's accompanying correspondence and some notes from his attendance at the meetings.
    - Board of Trustees meetings, 2011 Oct.-2013 May; 6 folders (Box 23)
    - Trustee manual, 2007 (Box 23)
    - Board of Trustees directories, 2007-2011 (Box 23)
    - Audit Committee, 2008-2009 (Box 23)
    - Scenario Planning Taskforce, 2008-2009 (Box 23)
    - Development Committee, 2012 (Box 23)
    - Ward/Ivory endowment, 1994-1997 (Box 23)
  - Ohio Humanities Council, 2007-2010; 12
    Appointment and meeting materials from Fleming's service on the Ohio Humanities Council.
    - Report to the Finance Committee, 2009 Feb 26 (Box 20)
    - Audited Financial Statements, 2007-2008 (Box 20)
    - Council meetings, 2008-2009; 7 folders (Box 20)
      The OHC met four times per year: March, June, October, and December. These files contain Fleming's meeting packets, correspondence, as well as grant applications and other materials he reviewed on behalf of the OHC.
    - Council meetings, 2009-2010; 4 folders (Box 21)
    - Grant review, 2008 Aug. (Box 21)
    - Advocacy Handbook from the Federation of State Humanities Council, 2008 (Box 21)
    - Humanities on the Hill, 2008-2009; 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Ohio Bicentennial Commission, 1987-2003; 15
    - Reports, 1997-2003 (Box 26)
    - Bicentennial of NW Ordinance and Constitution printed materials, 1987 (Box 26)
    - Nominating committee, 1996 (Box 26)
    - Commission meetings, 1997-2000; 5 folders (Box 26)
    - General correspondence, 1998-2000; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Member handbook, 1998 (Box 26)
  - The American Civil War Center at Historic Tredegar, 2001-2012; 16
    Fleming's materials collected from his role as a board member for Richmond's Historic Tredegar, including meeting materials, collections and management policies, events, and press. Materials document the evolution of Historic Tredegar and its eventual renovation and reopening as the American Civil War Center at Historic Tredegar.
    - Introduction to the project, 2001 Oct. (Box 27)
    - Board of Directors orientation manual, 2011-2012 (Box 27)
    - Board of Directors meetings, 2002-2008; 23 folders (Box 27)
      The BOT usually met three times per year. These files include meeting packets prepared for each BOT member as well as clippings, Fleming's accompanying correspondence, and some notes from his attendance at the meetings.
    - American Civil War Center Program Committee, 2004-2005 (Box 28)
    - Community Advisory Board meeting, 2001 Oct. (Box 28)
    - Congressional Advisory Board, 2002-2003 (Box 28)
    - Collections policy, 2006 (Box 28)
    - Emergency preparedness plan, 2006 Sept. (Box 28)
    - NEH planning grant, 2001-2002 (Box 28)
    - Fundraising, pledges, campaigns, 2001-2006 (Box 28)
    - Audience Research report, 2005 (Box 28)
    - Events, 2007 and undated (Box 28)
    - Dedication/opening, 2006 Oct. 6 (Box 28)
    - Press packets, undated (Box 28)
    - Press coverage, clippings, 2003-2006 (Box 28)
    - Newsletters, 2002-2006 (Box 28)
    - Union, Home, and Freedom video notes, preparations, 2002 (Box 28)
    - Exhibit text edits, drafts, 2005 (Box 28)
    - Exhibit designs, 2004 (Box 28)
    - Building designs, 2005 (Box 28)
- Museum Leadership, 1981-2014
  This series is grouped into subseries based on Fleming's work with each museum. Also includes his materials from the planning and production of the America I Am exhibit.
  - National Afro-American Museum and Cultural Center/Ohio Historical Society, 1981-2011; 4
    Contains Fleming's materials from his time as Project Director for the Ohio Historical Society (1980-1988) and subsequently materials from his role as Director of the National Afro-American Museum and Cultural Center in Wilberforce, Ohio (1988-1998). Includes both OHS personnel and administrative documents, as well as materials from the planning and construction the museum.
    - Bills, Acts, and Reports re: OHS and the NAAMCC, 1981-2004 (Box 8)
    - Federal Commission letter for the NAAMCC from James Morton Smith, 1986 Oct. 29 (Box 8)
      Photocopy, with annotations.
    - Commission meeting, 1986 Dec. 4-5; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Long-Range Plan 1987-1992, 1986 (Box 8)
    - Personnel policy, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Affirmative action policy, 1991 (Box 8)
    - Collections management manual, 1990 (Box 8)
    - Grievance/complaint policy, 1990 (Box 8)
    - ADA policy, 1991 (Box 8)
    - Employees policy, 1991 (Box 8)
    - Guide to Ohio Historical Society Sites, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Landmarks on the Frontier of Freedom: Black Historic Sites in Ohio, 1984 (Box 8)
    - Promotional image of planned NAAMCC building, undated (Box 8)
    - An Introduction to the National Afro-American Museum and Cultural Center Project, undated (Box 8)
    - This Legacy is Yours… booklet, undated (Box 8)
    - The Gold Torch article on the building of the NAAMCC, 1987 May 11 (Box 8)
    - Institutional Planning at OHS: A Beginning, 1990 Sept. 4 (Box 8)
    - Clippings re: groundbreaking for NAAMCC, 1982 (Box 8)
    - Press kits, 1984-1992 (Box 8)
    - Buttons and stamps, 1983 and undated (Box 8)
    - Event and exhibit posters, publicity, and publications, 1980s-1990s; 5 folders (Box 8)
    - Volunteer opportunities, undated (Box 9)
    - NAAMCC property issue, 2004 (Box 9)
    - Planning Council meetings, 1998-1999, 2011; 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Newsletters, 1989-2003; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - From Victory to Freedom: African American Life in the 1950s exhibit planning, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
    - The Real McCoy exhibition, 1991 (Box 9)
    - Uncommon Beauty in Common Objects exhibition, 1994; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - African American Creative Genius: A Sample of Innovations with Impact exhibition, undated (Box 9)
    - Clippings, 1980s-2000s (Box 9)
    - Museum Documents (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - National Underground Railroad Freedom Center, 1996-2004; 7
    Contains materials from the planning, design, and construction of the National Underground Railroad Freedom Center, where Fleming served as director from 1998 to 2000. Includes internal discussions, reports, and correspondence about the anticipated mission and scope of the NURFC, as well as feasability studies, publicity campaigns, and press coverage.
    - Feasibility study draft, 1996 July (Box 13)
    - Feasibility study, 1997 Jan. (Box 13)
    - Preliminary facility program, 1997 Aug. 22; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - NURFC notes, 1997-1998; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Feasibility study report for the NURFC, 1998 July (Box 13)
    - Phase II: Design/planning studies notes and documents, 1997-1999 (Box 13)
    - Meetings of the National Advisory Board, 1998 Sept. (Box 13)
    - Planning documents, 1998-1999 (Box 13)
    - Progress report, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Curriculum planning, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Documents re: permanent exhibits, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Story theater scripts, designs, and drafts, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Annual reports, 1998-1999 (Box 13)
    - 90 percent pre-design report, undated (Box 13)
    - Pre-design report, 1999 Mar. (Box 13)
    - Notes and correspondence re: planning the core exhibit, 1999; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Planning proposal for the research institute, 1998-1999 (Box 13)
    - Lighting Freedom's Flame publication, 1999 (Box 13)
    - Meeting notes, 1999 (Box 13)
    - Scott-Ford historic site interpretive conference, 1999 (Box 13)
    - Underground Railroad National Historic Landmark theme study, undated (Box 13)
    - Greene Co. Underground Railroad, undated (Box 13)
    - Underground Railroad conference, 1998 Nov. 21 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 14)
    - Campaign book, 2000 Apr. 24 (Box 14)
    - Planning documents, 2000 (Box 14)
    - When the Spirit Moves: the Africanization of American movement (notes and plans), 1999; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Correspondence re: links among core exhibit elements, 2000 Jan. (Box 14)
    - Meeting on Freedom and Slavery exhibit, 1999 May (Box 14)
    - Documents of correspondence re: Freedom and Slavery exhibit, 2000 (Box 14)
    - "Freedom and Slavery" exhibit schematic design, 2000 (Box 14)
    - Memo re: Freedom Center Organization, 2000 Dec. 8 (Box 14)
    - NURFC Board and administration, 2000-2001 (Box 14)
    - Mission and vision drafts, undated (Box 14)
    - World class media plan: year one, 2000 Oct. 18 (Box 14)
    - Collections roundtable discussion, 2000 March 30-31 (Box 14)
    - Roundtable discussion/brainstorming notes re: NURFC and exhibits, 2000 (Box 14)
    - Cincinnati: a Gateway to Freedom presentation, 2000 (Box 14)
    - Reassessing the public's interest in the Freedom Center: focus groups, 2000 Aug.-Oct. (Box 14)
    - Scholars' comments on "Storyline", 2000 (Box 14)
    - Appendix A: revised concept development schedule, 2000 (Box 14)
    - Freedom Station meeting in Seattle, 2000 Dec. (Box 14)
    - Senior Scholar Review meeeting documents, 2001 May 31 (Box 14)
    - Rouse report, 2000 (Box 14)
    - Scholar panel comments re: Slave jail artifact, 2001 (Box 14)
    - Free at Last (traveling exhibition) documents, undated (Box 15)
    - The Freedom Stations: a distributive program of the NURFC, 2002 May 15 (Box 15)
    - NPS National Underground Railroad Network to Freedom, undated (Box 15)